Hi everyone. Today I'm joined by Bailey,
CEO of Theta Data, the company that's
acquiring the Quamp Pie YouTube channel.
So Theta Data provides real time and
historical market data APIs used by
quants traders and developers worldwide.
Bailey, thanks for joining us.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> So Bailey, for those of you who for
those who don't know you, can you please
explain a little bit about your
background and what led you to start the
data?
>> Absolutely. When I was younger, I had a
fascination with options. In my younger
years, I dreamt of working at Citadel
like most of us. I majored in physics
and computer science at Stony Brook
University and I had the idea for the
data while I was studying there. Um,
when I started the company, I had this
light bulb moment. I immediately formed
the company the day I had the idea. Um,
and after a certain point, I decided to
go all in and max out my credit cards,
drop out of school, and pursue Theta
Data full-time. Uh, since then, it's
been a huge success, and I'm incredibly
thankful for it.
>> Wow. I actually didn't know that you um
dropped out of school for it.
Congratulations on um getting the
business up and running. And um
obviously it's it is a great success
because Theta data is known for
institutional grade market data um
delivered through its flexible APIs. How
do you describe your mission in one
sentence?
>> We look at data sets and we try to add
as much value to them as possible.
>> Now has that mission statement changed
over time?
>> Yes. So our original mission was to
democratize data. While I think this is
still one of our core values, it is not
our primary mission statement.
>> So beta data provides real-time
historical data for stocks and options
all the way down to the tick level with
low latency. Can you explain why your
end users that matters so much for the
quant and developers?
>> Absolutely. I think often times it's
important to see the full picture in the
market and the more messages you have
and the less filtering you're doing on
data and normalization
the better.
>> That makes a lot of sense and um yeah I
would second that being an end user
myself. So what motivated the data to
acquire this YouTube channel and
quantitative finance space?
>> That's a great question. We acquired
Quani to maintain it as a resource to
the Quan community. I also have a p
personal leg in this race. Um I've been
a follower of Quonai since you started
the channel and I want to keep Quai as
Quai.
>> Well that's awesome to hear and
obviously me as the channel founder I
really appreciate it Bailey. Um and as
you know uh our audience consists
largely of the students and aspiring
quants who want to enter the space. um
how will day-to-day data support the
content that's educational to those
users and those viewers rather than
being purely commercial. Our number one
goal is to maintain the status quo. We
take an all boats rise approach and hope
it continues as a resource for quants.
The style and the content at Quani will
remain largely unchanged.
>> Oh, well that's awesome. Um, I really
appreciate that and I'm sure our viewers
will appreciate consistency. Um, all the
same, can viewers expect new series or
deep dives into the real world
quantitative methods using beta data?
>> Absolutely. We plan to leverage our data
sets as well as other data sets to bring
you the same level of content you see
today.
And I guess um thinking about your main
users access right now to Theta Data um
using APIs, the documents and the
community server, will tutorials and the
developer support start becoming a focus
of this channel?
>> No, I mean we have our own YouTube
channel and we have a lot of content and
uh documentation elsewhere.
Quompai is not going to be part of you
know how to use data data um and basic
tutorials. We want to keep you know
quite true to why your subscribers uh
subscribe to Quai.
>> Excellent. So more the analytical
quantitative method approach.
>> That sounds um sounds very good and uh
really consistent.
Will uh will there be collaborations
with new content creators or even
student events in the future?
Yeah, it's it's funny you mentioned that
we're actually in talks with several
prominent quant creators at the moment
as as guest speakers. I think it will be
important to have a variety of uh
different speakers and uh perspectives
so we can have a higher breadth of
content.
>> Oh, well that's um really reassuring
that uh that this channel is going to
not only just survive but thrive um
without me. So, thank you very much uh
Bailey for having taken over the
channel. And I'm curious now if we take
a step back and we talk about the
industry um you sitting as the
perspective of a data provider with a
lot of successful firms um in your view
what is the next big shift in
quantitative finance data is it going to
be more artificial intelligence ML
integration more alternative data
streams what's next
>> I think that's a good question um
it's funny because I I feel that um alt
data
and call it AI or machine learning are
two sides of the same coin. Um I I think
given the the recent technological
advancements we've had in LLM, I think
that will unlock more capability with
extracting and analyzing all data. Uh so
I think both will become more prominent.
I also think when it comes to alt data,
it's very difficult to determine if a
singular alt data source is truth. And
oftentimes we see our more successful
clients using multiple adjacent alt data
sources to in in other words to
triangulate what is truth.
Oh, that's really interesting. Um,
especially on that last point that you
brought up. I think triangulating truth
is going to be a key feature to
successful um features and s signal
signals of anyone's model. So maybe
there is a um a future for data
providers like yourself to play the role
of ensemble modeling um and creating
maybe some cleaner signals not just
passing through data which you guys
don't do. You add value to the data
streams.
>> Yeah, absolutely. We're certainly in
talks about it.
>> And what's one piece of advice you'd
give students who want to break into the
quantitative space in 2026?
>> Relentlessly invest in yourself and your
skills and you are your most important
asset.
>> I would second that.
>> Hey Bailey, um thank you very much. I
really appreciate you coming on um
sharing your time and your vision about
what day-to-day does and where this
channel's going. Um for everyone
watching. Nothing changes here.
Educational content continues and this
channel will be the bridge as it always
has been between real industry tools
like the data and your quant career
journey.
Yeah. Thanks for watching guys and I
look forward to pushing out our first
video in the coming months. Very
exciting. Please feel free to reach out
to us if you have any questions or
suggestions. Our doors are open.